vam.ac.uk 2016-11-12

# Privacy policy and use of cookies - Victoria and Albert Museum

Your privacy is important to us. This page explains our online information practices and the choices you can make about how information about you is collected and used by the Victoria and Albert Museum here on this website and in other electronic communications networks.  

We may amend this privacy policy at any time by posting changes on this page. Amendments will automatically take effect upon publication. The last date of revision will always appear on the privacy policy.

 **Last updated: 18 September 2015**

* * *

## Web pages covered by this policy

This notice applies to all information collected or submitted on the Victoria and Albert Museum's domains www.vam.ac.uk and www.museumofchildhood.org.uk and includes areas of the website where you can create an account, comment on blogs, sign up for newsletters, enter competitions and book tickets for events or exhibitions as well as information collected automatically by cookies, if enabled.

For information about your protection while making an online purchase from the online V&A Shop, please refer to the [V&A Shop Privacy & Security](http://www.vam.ac.uk/content/articles/p/privacy-policy/) page.

The V&A is not responsible for the privacy policy of services on third party websites (for example Facebook, Twitter, YouTube, etc). You should refer to the appropriate privacy policies of each individual third party website for further information about them and their terms.

## The way we use information

You can browse the V&A sites without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself or your location. The websites collect some anonymous information about you automatically as you move through the site. We use this data to inform the development of our service (for example, we like to know which browsers most of our visitors are using). The information collected automatically in this way does not contain anything that can identify you personally. It provides data about what users do on the site, but not who they are.

Once you submit information to us you are no longer anonymous. Any personal information that you choose to give to us will be transferred and stored on secure local servers in a safe, confidential and secure environment.

We use the personal information you give us as a research tool to develop the content of the V&A's websites, to improve our understanding of our visitors and to determine better ways to serve you. We may use the information to provide you with details of the V&A's services and for this reason each screen that asks for data gives you the opportunity to opt out of receiving such information.

We use return e-mail addresses to answer e-mails we receive. Such addresses are not used for any other purpose and are not shared with outside parties. We will not send your data to third parties and we will not send data to areas where an adequate data protection policy is not in place.

## Use of cookies

Some sections of the V&A websites use cookies. Cookies are small, text-only strings of data which store information on the hard drive of your local computer or mobile device. Some cookies store data just for the time you are on the site. These are called session cookies and are not stored on your computer after you have left the site

These cookies do not contain any personal data about you individually. They are there to provide you with better information tailored to your individual needs. Most internet browsers are pre-set to accept cookies but if you prefer not to receive cookies, you can adjust your browser to refuse cookies, or to warn you when they are being used.

In the light of new legislation the V&A is making some changes to the websites and we provide you here with a register of the cookies which are currently deployed on our site.

 **When you visit V &A websites, if your browser is using the standard settings and it is accepting cookies, you are giving consent for cookies on the V&A sites to be stored on your computer. If you do not wish for this to happen, you can disable them in the settings of your browser.**

This has to be done on each different browser you use. For more information about how to disable cookies in different browsers, visit [Aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/Default.aspx?page=2)

The V&A websites works more efficiently if receipt of cookies is enabled, but it will still operate correctly if you disable cookies, although some extra enhanced features provided for you will not work. (For example the website will show you the last 4 pages you have visited on the site, but it cannot do this with out setting a cookie.)

### Cookies used on V&A websites

We use Google Analytics to collect information about site usage and performance. This helps us better understand our users and their needs so that we can continue to improve the services we provide. We also use this information to report to funders such as the Department for Culture, Media and Sport. The analytics cookies collect information such as the number of visits to the site, pages visited and international traffic. This information is anonymous and cannot be used to identify you personally.

This table lists the cookies that we use, how they help you use particular services, what type of cookie they are and the websites that are setting the cookies on your computer.

    Google Doubleclick  
| Various cookies used to store anonymous stats and sales data. Used to assess the success of marketing campaigns run by marketing partner  
| Max 30 days  
| persistent  
| vam.ac.uk and lovetheatre.com  
| iframe = fls.doubleclick  
  
---|---|---|---|---|---  
User survey 2012| Store non-personal data about survey responses to a web visitor survey in 2012. The survey asks you for your reason for visiting. Cookies are used to record the overall number of answers to the survey question and to link these to web stats. They do not store your personal data. The cookie is also used to allow the form to be hidden on your return visits. This is to prevent you from being shown the form again unnecessarily. This survey is part of a cross-organisational research project and (anonymous) data from this survey will be shared with other cultural organisations and research findings will be openly published. | 2 years| persistent| www.vam.ac.uk| ki_u, ki_s , ki_t  
Blogs on the site| Allows a logged in status to enable posting comments on blogs| Long term| persistent| www.vam.ac.uk| CHOCOL ATECHIP  
Recently viewed feature| maintains a list of recently viewed articles for your convenience| During visit only| session| www.vam.ac.uk| asset-id-history  
Press Images service| Ensures a malicious site is not trying to send data to our site via your browser| Long term typically 1 year| persistent| .vam.ac.uk| csrftoken  
Competitions| Used to check that information being sent is from a unique session.| Short term - typically a few days| persistent| .vam.ac.uk| e.g. SESS33a4ac4e08ac138784b7630530f32517  
AddThis (social media sharing options)| Record how much use there is of the social networking options provided (email a friend, send to Facebook etc). This information is only collected in aggregate form so we can tell which are the most popular tools.| Long term. Typically up to a few years| persistent| .vam.ac.uk| _csoot, __atuvc, uvc, psc, uid, uit, user_segment, dt, di, ssc, loc, _csuid  
Google Analytics on main website| Stores non-personal data about visits to the site for statistical reporting| Long term typically 2 years| persistent| .vam.ac.uk| __utma  
Google Analytics on main website| Stores non-personal data about visits to the site for statistical reporting| Short - typically 1 day| persistent| .vam.ac.uk| __utmb  
Google Analytics on main website| Stores non-personal data about visits to the site for statistical reporting| During visit only| session| .vam.ac.uk| __utmc  
Google Analytics on main website| Stores non-personal data about visits to the site for statistical reporting| Typically 6 months| persistent| .vam.ac.uk| __utmz  
Google Analytics on Museum of Childhood website| Stores non-personal data about visits to the site for statistical reporting| Long term typically 2 years| persistent| museumofchildhood.org.uk| __utma  
Google Analytics on Museum of Childhood website| Stores non-personal data about visits to the site for statistical reporting| Short - typically 1 day| persistent| museumofchildhood.org.uk| __utmb  
Google Analytics on Museum of Childhood website| Stores non-personal data about visits to the site for statistical reporting| During visit only| session| museumofchildhood.org.uk| __utmc  
Google Analytics on Museum of Childhood website| Stores non-personal data about visits to the site for statistical reporting| Typically 6 months| persistent| museumofchildhood.org.uk| __utmz  
Google Analytics on jobs pages| Stores non-personal data about visits to the site for statistical reporting| Typically 6 months| persistent| .peoplebank.com| __utmz  
Google Analytics on jobs pages| Stores non-personal data about visits to the site for statistical reporting| Long term typically 2 years| persistent| .peoplebank.com| __utma  
Google Analytics on jobs pages| Stores non-personal data about visits to the site for statistical reporting| Long term typically 2 years| persistent| .peoplebank.com| __unam  
  
### Flash cookies used on V&A websites

V&A websites have a number of interactive features on older parts of the site that use Flash. This is widely used to provide games, video and other interactive content. Many web browsers will have a version of the Flash player that plays these files.  The Flash player can store data in a similar way to standard cookies, using a data file called a Local Shared Object.

This table lists Local Shared Objects that may be stored from within interactives on V&A websites. We have quite a number of older interactives using Flash. We are aware of a small number of local shared objects created by Flash features. These are used to make them work more easily and are listed below.  However, it is not possible to tell for every one of the Flash interactives if they store any data in a Flash cookie. We are phasing out older interactives

For more information on how to control Flash cookies (Local Shared Objects) visit the [Adobe website.](http://www.adobe.com/security/flashplayer/articles/lso/)

What service is setting the cookie| What the cookie does| How long does the cookie last| Type| What website can access the cookie (domain)| Name of cookie  
---|---|---|---|---|---  
Design a Renaissance Room| Remembers and retains the layout settings when designing a room interior, in an interactive game, to prevent these having to be re-entered each time.| permanent unless deleted| persistent| www.vam.ac.uk| room_builder.sol  
Design a Renaissance Room| Remembers and retains the layout settings when designing a room interior, in an interactive game, to prevent these having to be re-entered each time.| permanent unless deleted| persistent| www.vam.ac.uk| room_nav_intro.sol  
Vivienne Westwood - Design a tartan| Remembers and retains the layout settings when designing a tartan in an interactive game to prevent these having to be re-entered each time.| permanent unless deleted| persistent| www.vam.ac.uk| va_tartan.sol  
Design a Renaissance Room| Stores non-personal statistical data about visit to interactive| permanent unless deleted| persistent| www.vam.ac.uk| analytics.sol  
  
### Cookies used on third party websites that provide services to V&A visitors

Certain areas of the website will also contain third party cookies, e.g. embedded Flickr or YouTube content. The V&A is not responsible for these cookies and you should refer to the appropriate third party website Privacy Policy for further information about them and their terms.

  What service is setting the cookie| What the cookie does| How long does the cookie last| Type| What website can access the cookie (domain)| Name of cookie  
---|---|---|---|---|---  
Google Doubleclick  
| Various cookies used to store anonymous stats and sales data. Used to assess the success of marketing campaigns run by marketing partner  
| Max 30 days  
| persistent  
| vam.ac.uk and lovetheatre.com  
| iframe = fls.doubleclick  
  
Facebook options on V&A web pages| Stores non-personal data about use of Facebook share option on the V&A site| During visit only| session| facebook.com| reg_fb_gate  
Facebook options on V&A web pages| Stores non-personal data about use of Facebook share option on the V&A site| During visit only| session| facebook.com| reg_fb_ref  
Facebook options on V&A web pages| Stores non-personal data about use of Facebook share option on the V&A site| Variable typically 1 week| persistent| facebook.com| _e_1k0M_0  
Quantcast  
| Two main types of cookies are used: (1) Quantcast Measure and (2) Quantcast Advertise. Our Measure product helps websites owners to anonymously understand the characteristics and demographics of the people who visit their sites. Our Advertise product allows businesses to deliver relevant online advertising to individual consumers. When you visit a site or app operated by a Quantcast Partner, the Partner permits us to collect Log Data. The Log Data we store is not Personally Identifiable Information (PII). We only know you as an anonymous unique identifier, and we associate information about your site visits or app usage with that identifier, not with your name or email address or any other Personally Identifiable Information.  
| Max 30 days  
| persistent  
| vam.ac.uk  
| quantserve.com  
  
Simek Ad Serving  
| Various cookies used to store anonymous stats and sales data. Used to assess the success of marketing campaigns run by marketing partner  
| Max 30 days  
| persistent  
| vam.ac.uk  
| bs.serving-sys.com/Serving  
  
Videos served on V&A websites hosted on V&A Vimeo account| Various cookies used to store anonymous stats data and view option settings about where a video can be embedded on V&A and other web pages| variable| session| vimeo.com| __utmz  
Videos served on V&A websites hosted on V&A Vimeo account| Various cookies used to store anonymous stats data and view option settings about where a video can be embedded on V&A and other web pages. Blocking these may affect playback of video embedded in V&A web pages| variable. Typically from few days to several years| persistent| vimeo.com| Various- __utmz, __utma, vimeo, stats_start_date, stats_end_date, v6, __utmv, _home_active_tab, uid  
Twitter feeds embedded on V&A web pages| Stores non-personal data about use of Twitter embedded on the V&A site. Some cookies may only be set when accessing twitter.com directly. Refer to Twitter site for details| variable| session+persistent| twitter.com| Various- __utmz, __utma, auth_token, auth_token_session, external referrer, guest_id, js, k, lang, pid, secrure_session, twid, twll  
Comments on blogs on Museum of Childhood website| Various cookies used to store anonymous stats data and view option settings about where a blog comment can be added to the Museum of Childhood blog pages. Blocking these may affect the ability to comment on Museum of Childhood blogs.| variable| session+persistent| intensedebate.com/, wordpress.org/, openid.net/| _utmc, _utmc, _utmb, _utma, idcomments_token, idcomments_userid, login_pref, _qca  
Google Plus share options on V&A web pages| Stores non-personal data about use of Google+ share option on the V&A site.| Short term.| persistent| plusone.google.com| BEAT  
Google including Google Plus| Stores non-personal data about use of Google+ share option on the V&A site| During visit only| session| api.google.com, plus.google.com, plusone.goole.com| ULS  
Total Media| Used to assess the success of marketing campaigns run by marketing partner| Long term. May vary, but typically several years| persistent| mediaplex.com| mojo3, SVID  
ADROLL  
| Used to present advertisements based on products/services viewed on the V&A Shop and V&A websites.  
| Expiry of 30 days  
| persistent  
| vam.ac.uk| __ar_v4  

## When we may use your details to contact you

If you do opt to provide us with any personal information we use this in various ways:

### Competitions.

Winners of competitions are notified directly by the V&A, unless stated otherwise in the competition Terms & Conditions. The V&A Marketing Department keep information gathered through web competitions for approximately three months on a secure local server. Entrants who have agreed to be sent third-party information have their contact details sent to the relevant organisations. Entrants who have declined to receive further information will have their contact details deleted from the server after approximately three months. 

### E-newsletters.

All users who agree to be sent an e-newsletter via the web are sent through automatically to the web subscription page. The data you provide when signing up is stored securely and for V&A use only. You can unsubscribe from email newsletters at any time by clicking on the link that appears at the bottom of every newsletter. 

### Social Networks.

Where we are active on third party sites which feature social networking or sharing (Facebook, Twitter, Flickr, Pinterest etc) we may very occasionally contact you directly in relation to activities we are running on those sites. 

### User ID and web contributions.

If you submit content to V&A websites under a user name or create a user account, your user ID will be visible to the public alongside any submission you make. No other private information will be viewable. You can access all your personal identifiable information that we collect online and maintain by logging in to your account and viewing your profile page. You can correct factual errors in your personally identifiable information within your account via your profile page or by sending the webmaster a request that credibly shows error. Amendments or deletions to personal information will roll out to all activity you have had on the site.

To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identify before granting access and making corrections.

## Links to non-V&A websites

The V&A accepts no responsibility or liability for content on third party websites. Users clicking on links to external sites should check the Terms and Conditions and Privacy Policy of the site they are visiting.

### Our commitment to data security

To prevent unauthorised access, maintain data accuracy and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

### How to contact us

If you have any questions or concerns about our privacy policy, please e-mail us at: [webmaster@vam.ac.uk](mailto:webmaster@vam.ac.uk%20)
